<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yiren Zhou</title>
    <link>https://yirzhou.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Yiren Zhou</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yirzhou.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Last Christmas</title>
      <link>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/last-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/last-christmas/</guid>
      <description>Yet another Christmas, but it is the last Christmas I will be having in Canada. This year&amp;rsquo;s Christmas obviously feels drastically different from the others because of the current world we live in, and I want to capture the feelings I have right now, in case I want to refer back in the future.
Perfect snow This Christmas actually feels like a Christmas in terms of the weather - it started snowing on Christmas Eve and will probably keep snowing for a couple of days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfect Sandbox Environment for C&#43;&#43; Development</title>
      <link>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/vscode-remote-containers-cpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/vscode-remote-containers-cpp/</guid>
      <description>This is one of the most valuable skills that I learned in my current internship. We all love VSCode but this just blew me away.
 1. Motivation As a software engineer working with various languages and their ecosystems, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to mess up your development machine when installing dependencies directly on it. Even when we just want to try out a new language, we still need to have that language runtime installed somewhere on our system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Beginning</title>
      <link>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/a-new-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 17:46:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/a-new-beginning/</guid>
      <description>This is my first ever article on this site, which means that I&amp;rsquo;m just as new to it as you are 🙂.
Some history I&amp;rsquo;ve had this idea of writing random stuff down for quite a while, and I&amp;rsquo;ve had two failed attempts in the past.
My first attempt was a WordPress site with a paid hosting service. It was my very first entry into content management. However, I found WordPress too much overkill for my use as there are a lot of features that I never used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://yirzhou.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yirzhou.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, my name is Yiren, and I also go by Larry. I am a 4th-year computer engineering student at the University of Waterloo, although I&amp;rsquo;ll be graduating soon in April 2021 😃.
I consider myself a weird tech nerd: I don&amp;rsquo;t play games (any more) but I know pretty much everything about the latest CPU and GPU releases; I don&amp;rsquo;t own any cutting-edge tech products, but I try to keep myself updated with their unique features.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
