<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Yiren Zhou</title>
    <link>https://yirzhou.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Yiren Zhou</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yirzhou.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>March Update</title>
      <link>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/march-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/march-update/</guid>
      <description>The final term at school has been tough to say the least because:
 I am taking seven courses. I am missing home too much. I have been rejected by three grad schools that I applied to. Physically, I am not in a good shape.  The first two reasons can be coped fairly easily by: studying harder and sleeping less, and distracting myself by reading and watching interesting stuff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Stuff Done Feels Good Again</title>
      <link>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/getting-stuff-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/getting-stuff-done/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been three weeks since my last post. Taking seven courses in a term isn&amp;rsquo;t the easiest thing to do&amp;hellip; I struggled a bit at the beginning of the term because all the tasks and deadlines were just overwhelming.
However, recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve started doing something that I used to do and that&amp;rsquo;s made me feel so good about myself. That is: using a TODO app.
I know it sounds incredibly boring to pretty much everyone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using AWS JavaScript SDK v3 in Browsers</title>
      <link>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/aws-js-sdk-v3-in-browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/aws-js-sdk-v3-in-browser/</guid>
      <description>In this article, I will walkthrough the process of incorporating the &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; AWS JavaScript SDK in a web application, particularly how to use it directly in browsers.
I wrote this because I found relevant documentation a bit lacking. Also, the idea can be applied to using TypeScript in browsers in general.
Introduction to AWS SDK for JavaScript v3 AWS have recently released Version 3 of the SDK for JavaScript, targeting the following issues of its previous version (V2):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Googletest with CMake</title>
      <link>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/googletest-with-cmake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/googletest-with-cmake/</guid>
      <description>Background Welcome to 2021. This is my first article for this year and I want to start with a useful tip for C++ unit testing. Unlike other languages, unit testing in C++ has never been as straightforward. However, googletest (also known as &amp;ldquo;gtest&amp;rdquo;) has been one of the more well-received testing framework in various organizations, so that&amp;rsquo;s what I will focus on.
What makes this article slightly different is that unlike the traditional way of defining an entry point for your testing program (ie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Thoughts on 2020</title>
      <link>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/thoughts-on-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/thoughts-on-2020/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been hell of a year&amp;hellip; damn!
I have envisioned a very different year for 2020 back in 2019 - 2020 was supposed to be normal and balanced (again, like all things should be), and yet we had this: a year that might&amp;rsquo;ve already led us into a completely different future. I have come across this thought multiple times: when everything goes back to normal, the perfect term that describes that feeling would be: post-apocalyptic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Different Christmas Vibe</title>
      <link>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/last-christmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/last-christmas/</guid>
      <description>Yet another Christmas, but it is the last Christmas I will be having in Canada. This year&amp;rsquo;s Christmas obviously feels drastically different from the others because of the current world we live in, and I want to capture the feelings I have right now, in case I want to refer back in the future.
Perfect snow This Christmas actually feels like a Christmas in terms of the weather - it started snowing on Christmas Eve and will probably keep snowing for a couple of days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfect Sandbox Environment for C&#43;&#43; Development</title>
      <link>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/vscode-remote-containers-cpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/vscode-remote-containers-cpp/</guid>
      <description>This is one of the most valuable skills that I learned in my current internship. We all love VSCode but this just blew me away.
 1. Motivation As a software engineer working with various languages and their ecosystems, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to mess up your development machine when installing dependencies directly on it. Even when we just want to try out a new language, we still need to have that language runtime installed somewhere on our system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Beginning</title>
      <link>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/a-new-beginning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 17:46:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yirzhou.github.io/posts/a-new-beginning/</guid>
      <description>This is my first ever article on this site, which means that I&amp;rsquo;m just as new to it as you are 🙂.
Some history I&amp;rsquo;ve had this idea of writing random stuff down for quite a while, and I&amp;rsquo;ve had two failed attempts in the past.
My first attempt was a WordPress site with a paid hosting service. It was my very first entry into content management. However, I found WordPress too much overkill for my use as there are a lot of features that I never used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://yirzhou.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yirzhou.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, my name is Yiren, and I also go by Larry. I am a 4th-year computer engineering student at the University of Waterloo, although I&amp;rsquo;ll be graduating soon in April 2021 😃.
I consider myself a weird tech nerd: I don&amp;rsquo;t play games (any more) but I know pretty much everything about the latest CPU and GPU releases; I don&amp;rsquo;t own any cutting-edge tech products, but I try to keep myself updated with their unique features.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
